avidarticles.com 2011-06-07

# Avid Articles Free Content For Your Website Ezine or Blog avidarticles.com

Avid Articles Privacy Policy

Avid Articles aims to provide services to authors and publishers as well as other parties who may have an interest in the material produced by our member authors. We use Internet technology to achieve this and we aim to provide an interactive and personalized experience.

We may use Personally Identifiable Information (including your name, e-mail address, postal address, telephone number) and it is our aim at all times to be guided by the terms of this privacy policy.

We will never disclose your email address to any third party unless that third party is providing Avid Articles with services on an out sourcing basis and in that event any such third party would be bound by the same procedures as we observe in house. Your email address and other personal details will never be disclosed to any other party except as directed by a court where all the correct formalities have been complied with.

How we gather information from users

How we collect and store information depends on the particular page you are visiting, the activities you participate in and the services we are providing you. You may for example provide us with registration information for particular services when you register for access to certain parts of our site or request certain facilities such as newsletters or at any such time as you make a purchase. 

You may provide information when you participate in contests or competitions, forums or chat rooms and other interactive areas of our site. In common with most Web sites, Avid Articles also collects information automatically and through the use of technologies that may not be obvious to our visitors. 

To improve the quality of your visit we may log the name of your Internet Service Provider or use cookie technology to recognize you and hold certain information regarding your visit. The cookie may among other things store your user name and password which is designed to spare you from having to re-enter that information on every occasion that you visit, or possibly control the number of times you encounter particular promotional material while visiting our site. With the uptake of additional technology, we may in the future gather information by other means. You may be able in certain cases to choose not to provide us with information - for example by setting your browser to not accept cookies but if you were to do this you may be unable to access certain parts of the site or you may be asked to re-enter your user name and password. In addition, we may no longer be able to customize the site's features according to your preferences.

What we do with the information we collect

Like other Web publishers, we collect information to enhance your visit and deliver more individualized content and advertising. We respect your privacy and do not share your information with anyone. 

Aggregated Information (information that does not personally identify you) may be used in many ways. We may combine information about usage patterns by one or more users to help improve our site and services (such as to determine pages visited or features that users find most attractive). Aggregated Information may occasionally be shared with advertisers and business partners. This is anonymous information and does not allow anyone to identify you individually.

We may use your Personally Identifiable Information to discuss with you:

* your registration and customization preferences 
* our Terms of Service and Privacy Policy 
* services and products offered by Avid Articles
* other areas we think you might find of interest. 

Personally Identifiable Information collected by Avid Articles may also be used for other purposes. This may include but is not limited to site troubleshooting, administration, transaction processing, administration of competitions and various other matters. Trusted third parties who provide technical services for the operation of our site (our web host for example) may access such information. We will use your information only as permitted by law. 

In addition, as we continue to develop our business, we may sell, buy, merge or partner with other businesses. When this type of activity takes place, user information may be among the transferred assets. We may also disclose your information in response to a court order, whenever we believe we are reasonably required to do so by law, in connection with the collection of monies you may owe to us, and or to law enforcement agencies authorities whenever we believe it to be appropriate or necessary to do so. Please note we may not be permitted to provide you with notice prior to or after disclosure in such cases.

Affiliated sites, linked sites and advertisements

Avid Articles expects all persons or businesses with whom we deal to respect the privacy of our users. You must understand, however, that third parties including our advertisers, partners, affiliates and other content providers accessible through our site may have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices. For example, during your visit to our site you may view content that is actually created or hosted by a third party. Also, through Avid Articles you may be introduced to or be able to access information or services offered by other parties. Avid Articles is not responsible for the actions or policies of such third parties and therefore you should check the applicable privacy policies of those third parties when providing information on a feature or page operated by a third party.

While on our site, any of our business partners may use cookies or other technology to attempt to identify some of your preferences or retrieve information about you. Some of our advertising is served by third parties and may include cookies that enable the advertiser to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before. Other features available on our site may involve third parties and may use cookies or other technology to gather information.Avid Articles does not control the use of this technology or the resulting information when operated by other parties and Avid Articles is not responsible for the actions or policies of such third parties.You should also be aware that if you voluntarily disclose Personally Identifiable Information on forums or in discussion areas, that information can be viewed publicly and can be collected and used by third parties without our knowledge and may result in unsolicited messages from other individuals or third parties. Such activities are beyond the control of Avid Articles and this policy and you should exercise appropriate caution. 

Children

Avid Articles does not knowingly collect or solicit Personally Identifiable Information from or about children under the age of 13. If we discover we have received any information from a child under 13 in violation of this policy, we will delete that information immediately. Please remember that rules concerning the processing of data vary from country to country. If you believe Avid Articles has any information from or about anyone under 13, please contact us via our support desk.

Contacting Us

We can be reached by leaving a message at our support desk. (* LINK*)

Changes to this Policy

Avid Articles reserves the right to change this policy at any time. Your continued use of our site following the posting of changes to these terms will indicate that you accept the alterations. Please check this page periodically for changes. Information collected prior to the time that any change is notified will be used in accordance with the rules and laws that applied at the time that the information was collected.

Governing law

This policy and the use of this Site are governed by English law. This statement and the policies outlined herein are not intended to and do not create any contractual or other legal rights in or on behalf of any party.
